{
  "questions": [
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 13th century",
        "B. 14th century",
        "C. 15th century",
        "D. 10th century"
      ],
      "question": "Ibn Battuta, the celebrated traveler visited Assam in the",
      "answer": "B. 14th century"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Suryakhan Daikegya",
        "B. Dibar and Dodosai",
        "C. Sukumar Barkaith",
        "D. Rama Saraswati"
      ],
      "question": "The illustration work of the medieval Assamese text Hastividyarnava was done by",
      "answer": "C. Sukumar Barkaith"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nara Narayan",
        "B. Parkshit Narayan",
        "C. Biswa Singha",
        "D. Raghu Dev"
      ],
      "question": "Gohain Kamal Ali constructed by Gohain Kamal from Koch Bihar to Narayanpur was constructed during the reign of",
      "answer": "A. Nara Narayan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rudra Singha",
        "B. Siva Singha",
        "C. Rajeswar Singha",
        "D. Pramatta Singha"
      ],
      "question": "Rang Ghar was constructed during the period of",
      "answer": "D. Pramatta Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Indra Narayan",
        "B. Joso Narayan",
        "C. Nirbhya Narayan",
        "D. Durlabh Narayan"
      ],
      "question": "The Kachari king to assume the title Pratap Narayan after defeating the Ahom was",
      "answer": "A. Indra Narayan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Ram Saraswati",
        "B. Ananta Kandali",
        "C. Sankardeva",
        "D. Madhav Kandali"
      ],
      "question": "Who among the literatures did not receive the patronage of Koch king Naranarayan ?",
      "answer": "D. Madhav Kandali"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Alberuni",
        "B. Azan Fakir",
        "C. Mir Jumla",
        "D. Shihabuddin Tallish"
      ],
      "question": "Fatiyah-i-Ibryah was written by",
      "answer": "D. Shihabuddin Tallish"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sankardeva",
        "B. Madhav Kandali",
        "C. Ananta Kandali",
        "D. Ram Saraswati"
      ],
      "question": "Who among the following is the first Assamese translator of Ramayana?",
      "answer": "B. Madhav Kandali"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karbi Anglong",
        "B. Khasi-Jaintia (Meghalaya)",
        "C. Manipur",
        "D. Tripura"
      ],
      "question": "The Barak or Surma river of Cacher originates from",
      "answer": "C. Manipur"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Shiva Singha",
        "B. Pratap Singha",
        "C. Jayadhvaj Singha",
        "D. Suhungmung"
      ],
      "question": "The first Ahom Monarch to assume the Hindu title Swarga Narayan of was",
      "answer": "D. Suhungmung"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Borphukan",
        "B. Rajkhowa",
        "C. Barpatra Gohain",
        "D. Khongea Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The title of overall administration head of lower Assam Region during the Ahom rule was",
      "answer": "A. Borphukan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandrakanta Singha",
        "B. Kamaleshwar Singha",
        "C. Jogeshwar Singha",
        "D. Purandar Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The independent Ahom king was",
      "answer": "D. Purandar Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Zamindar",
        "B. King",
        "C. Frontier Officer",
        "D. Naval Commander"
      ],
      "question": "Sadiya Khowa Gohain was a",
      "answer": "C. Frontier Officer"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sutiyampha",
        "B. Sutamla",
        "C. Surampha",
        "D. Sunyatpha"
      ],
      "question": "The King nicknamed as Bhagaraja was",
      "answer": "C. Surampha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Elaborate burial tanks of Ahom nobility are kings",
        "B. Large fields",
        "C. Temples",
        "D. Enclosure for sporting activities"
      ],
      "question": "Maidams are",
      "answer": "A. Elaborate burial tanks of Ahom nobility are kings"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sudangpha Raja",
        "B. Suhungmung Dihingia",
        "C. Pratap Singha",
        "D. Jayadhvaj Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The officer of the Barbarua and Barphukan is created by",
      "answer": "C. Pratap Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Shiva Singha",
        "B. Pramatta Singha",
        "C. Rajehwar Singha",
        "D. Lakshmi Singha"
      ],
      "question": "Rudra Singha built the Rang Ghar with Bamboo and WooD. It was built by brick and motor by",
      "answer": "B. Pramatta Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rajmantri Atanu Borgohain Dihingia Raja",
        "B. Koliabhumora Barphukan",
        "C. Miri Sandiloi",
        "D. Manthir Bharali Barua"
      ],
      "question": "In the Battle of Saraighat next to Lachit Barphukan was in the leadership of",
      "answer": "A. Rajmantri Atanu Borgohain Dihingia Raja"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandrakanta Singha",
        "B. Kamaleshwar Singha",
        "C. Jogeswar Singha",
        "D. Purandar Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The last independent Ahom King was",
      "answer": "D. Purandar Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. East India Company and Ahom King",
        "B. East India Company and Burmese",
        "C. British King and the Ahom King",
        "D. Ahom King and Burmese"
      ],
      "question": "The Treaty of Yandaboo was signed in 1826 between",
      "answer": "B. East India Company and Burmese"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Lakshminath Bezbaruah",
        "B. Chandrakumar Agarwalla",
        "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "Who did not belong to Jonaki Yug?",
      "answer": "D. None of the above"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Piyali phukan",
        "B. Maniram Dewan",
        "C. Gomdhar Konwar",
        "D. Piyali Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The first rebellion against the British rule in Assam in 1828 was led by",
      "answer": "C. Gomdhar Konwar"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chittagong",
        "B. Khulna",
        "C. Sylhet",
        "D. Shala Shakar"
      ],
      "question": "Which district was separated from Assam and given to East Pakistan?",
      "answer": "C. Sylhet"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sivsagar",
        "B. Lakhimpur",
        "C. Golaghat",
        "D. Sylhet"
      ],
      "question": "Under the Mountbatten plan, a referendum in Assam was to be held in the district of",
      "answer": "D. Sylhet"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandraprabha Saikiani",
        "B. Pushpalata Das",
        "C. Rani Gaidinliu",
        "D. None of them"
      ],
      "question": "A pioneer lady responsible for farming the Mrityu Bahini in Assam in connection with the freedom struggle of the country as",
      "answer": "B. Pushpalata Das"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Quit India Movement",
        "B. Civil Disobedience Movement",
        "C. Non-Cooperation Movement",
        "D. Ahom Association"
      ],
      "question": "The shanti Sena Force was formed in Assam during the independence movement before the commencement of the",
      "answer": "A. Quit India Movement"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1920",
        "B. 1921",
        "C. 1922",
        "D. 1923"
      ],
      "question": "When was Assam Provincial Congress formed?",
      "answer": "B. 1921"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nathan Brown",
        "B. Jatindranath Duwara",
        "C. Debendranath Bezbarua",
        "D. Gunabhiram Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The author of Asomiya Sahityar Buranji is",
      "answer": "C. Debendranath Bezbarua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1874",
        "B. 1889",
        "C. 1861",
        "D. 1826"
      ],
      "question": "The Assam region was separated from the Bengal presidency in",
      "answer": "A. 1874"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. August 1942",
        "B. August 1842",
        "C. September 1942",
        "D. August 1941"
      ],
      "question": "The British-made aerodrome at Barnagar, Sarbhog, was set ablaze under the leadership of Brajanath Sarma in",
      "answer": "A. August 1942"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dutiram Barua",
        "B. Piyali Barua",
        "C. Piyali Phukan",
        "D. Farmud Ali"
      ],
      "question": "Who was hanged with Maniram Dewan?",
      "answer": "B. Piyali Barua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Phulaguri Dhawa",
        "B. Rangia Revolt",
        "C. Patharughat Revolt",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "question": "Year 1894 is  related to",
      "answer": "C. Patharughat Revolt"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Assamese was reinstated as an official language of Assam",
        "B. Bengali was introduced as an official language of Assam",
        "C. First Assamese novel was published",
        "D. First magazine was published from Calcutta"
      ],
      "question": "1836 was crucial in case of Assamese language and literature because",
      "answer": "B. Bengali was introduced as an official language of Assam"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Garo",
        "B. Bodos",
        "C. Missing",
        "D. Rabha"
      ],
      "question": "Bagurumba is a folk dance performed by:",
      "answer": "B. Bodos"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Cane",
        "B. Bamboo",
        "C. Buffalo horn",
        "D. Teakwood"
      ],
      "question": "Gagana is a famous musical instrument of Assam made up of",
      "answer": "B. Bamboo"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 80,645 km2",
        "B. 78,438 km2",
        "C. 79,012 km2",
        "D. 77,901 km2"
      ],
      "question": "The total area of Assam is",
      "answer": "B. 78,438 km2"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. North zone",
        "B. East zone",
        "C. South zone",
        "D. West zone"
      ],
      "question": "Terai zone is situated at Assam’s"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 3.39 per cent",
        "B. 2.39 per cent",
        "C. 4.39 per cent",
        "D. 2.93 per cent"
      ],
      "question": "How much percent of the Indian landmass is covered by the state of Assam?",
      "answer": "B. 2.39 per cent"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Graphite",
        "B. Rock Salt",
        "C. Limestone",
        "D. Coal"
      ],
      "question": "North Cacher Hill is known for",
      "answer": "C. Limestone"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bodoland Area",
        "B. North Cacher Hill Area",
        "C. Barak Valley Region",
        "D. Brahmaputra Valley Region"
      ],
      "question": "In Assam, Red soil is the main feature of",
      "answer": "B. North Cacher Hill Area"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup",
        "B. Goalpara and Kokrajhar",
        "C. Bongaigaon and Kokrajhar",
        "D. Darang, Barpeta and Nalbari"
      ],
      "question": "Baksa district of Assam was created from the parts of which of the following districts?",
      "answer": "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tropical climate",
        "B. Hot climate",
        "C. Warm Climate",
        "D. Cold climate"
      ],
      "question": "Assam state enjoys",
      "answer": "A. Tropical climate"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nameri",
        "B. Dibru Saikhowa",
        "C. Manas",
        "D. Orang"
      ],
      "question": "The National Park of Assam where the rare winged duck (deohanh) is found in",
      "answer": "A. Nameri"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 33 per cent",
        "B. 22 per cent",
        "C. 28 per cent",
        "D. 19 per cent"
      ],
      "question": "Of the total geographical area of Assam the total area under the forest is",
      "answer": "B. 22 per cent"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1974",
        "B. 1975",
        "C. 1976",
        "D. 1977"
      ],
      "question": "In which year, Kaziranga Wildlife Sanctuary was elevated to a National Park?",
      "answer": "A. 1974"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat",
        "B. Golaghat",
        "C. Sivsagar",
        "D. Dhemaji"
      ],
      "question": "Pani Dihing Birds Sanctuary is located in which of the following districts of Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Sivsagar"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kaziranga, Manas, Nameri, Dibru Saikhowa, Orang",
        "B. Manas, Kaziranga, Dibru Saikhowa, Nameri, Orang",
        "C. Kaziranga, Manas, Nameri, Orang, Dibru Saikhowa",
        "D. Manas, Dibru Saikhowa, Kaziranga, Orang, Nameri"
      ],
      "question": "Arrange the National Parks of Assam correctly in the order of descending size",
      "answer": "B. Manas, Kaziranga, Dibru Saikhowa, Nameri, Orang"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. State Cabinet",
        "B. Parliament",
        "C. State Legislature",
        "D. State Public Service Commission"
      ],
      "question": "The Governor of a state is an integral part of the",
      "answer": "C. State Legislature"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. The Speaker of the Lok Sabha and the Speaker of State Legislative Assembly",
        "B. The Solicitor General of India and the Advocate General of the State",
        "C. The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of India and the Chief Justice of High Court of the State",
        "D. None of them"
      ],
      "question": "Who administer the Oath of Office for the president of India and the Governor of a State respectively?",
      "answer": "C. The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of India and the Chief Justice of High Court of the State"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1 Year",
        "B. 6 months",
        "C. 3 months",
        "D. Indefinite"
      ],
      "question": "The maximum permissible period between two sessions of a state legislature Assembly is:",
      "answer": "B. 6 months"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Article 220",
        "B. Article 229",
        "C. Article 224",
        "D. Article 231"
      ],
      "question": "Under which of the following Articles, additional and acting judges can be appointed in the High Courts?",
      "answer": "C. Article 224"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. The Governor",
        "B. The judges of the High Court",
        "C. The Chief Minister",
        "D. The President"
      ],
      "question": "In India, who appoints the District Judges?",
      "answer": "A. The Governor"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat Tea Company",
        "B. Assam Tea Company",
        "C. Assam – Bengal Tea Company",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "The first tea company established in Assam was",
      "answer": "B. Assam Tea Company"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Brass – smiths",
        "B. Bell metal – smiths",
        "C. Ivory artists",
        "D. Potters and blacksmiths"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following cottage industry workers in Assam suffer most due to the paucity of raw material?",
      "answer": "C. Ivory artists"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Goalpara District",
        "B. Barak Valley",
        "C. Dhubri District",
        "D. Tinsukia District"
      ],
      "question": "The terra – cotta industry in Assam has developed in",
      "answer": "C. Dhubri District"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Oxo – alcohols",
        "B. Portland cement and hollow bricks",
        "C. Ethylene and propylene",
        "D. Polyethylene"
      ],
      "question": "The Assam Gas Cracker Project does not have the proposal to produce",
      "answer": "B. Portland cement and hollow bricks"
    }
  ]
}
